All right. So, you've learned about how
to manipulate text. It's time to learn
how to manipulate numbers. In
JavaScript, there are a couple of
operations that you can perform on
numbers. And I'm going to show you those
right now. So, um the common operators
that you can do with numbers is you can
add, you can subtract, you can multiply,
you can divide, and you can use what's
called the modulus operator. Um in this
video, we're just going to talk about
the first four. In the next video, I'll
give you a breakdown of how the modulus
operator works. And then after that,
we'll talk about how to use it. Um, but
for now, let's say you have a number.
So, we'll say we'll create a variable.
We'll say let my num one equal. And
let's just do five right now. And we'll
say let my num 2 equal
15.
If we want to add those two numbers, um,
just as expected, it is the plus sign.
So, we could say alert my num one plus
my num two. And if we save that and we
go live or if you're already live, you
can just switch over to your live
website. Um, you can see 5 + 15 is 20.
And that is exactly what we would expect
if we did addition. Um,
if we subtract
my num one from my num two and save and
we go over to our web page, we can see
that it's 10. 15 - 5 is 10. So, exactly
what we would expect. We're to come back
over. Um, we could do 15 because that's
what my number two is divided by 5. And
if we come over, we see the answer is
three, just like we'd expect. Um, and
then if we do 15 * 5 and we save that
and we come over, we can see it's 75.
And I am just now realizing I forgot an
operator. Um, if you used a double
asterisk, that is for um an exponent. So
if
we wanted to raise five to the second
power, we would say my num one and then
double asterisk and then my num two. So
that is the same as raising 5 to the
second power. So if we save that, 5^
squar is 25. And sure enough, there's
25. All right. So just as a review,
addition is the plus sign. Subtraction
is the hyphen or the dash.
Multiplication is the asterisk. Division
is a single forward slash. You can find
the forward slash underneath the
question mark next to your right hand
shift key. Um, and then the double
asterisk is for exponentiation. That is
on the number eight. So you'd hold shift
and eight and that's how you get a
single asterisk. Do that twice and you
get your double asterisk. And then in
the next video we'll talk about modulus.
Modulus is above your number five key.
And that concludes this video. Thanks
for watching.